Sayed Abdul Karim

sakarim9124@gmail.com 08296708008 Bangalore, Karnātaka

Work Links

GitHub - https://github.com/sayedabdulkarim

Portfolio - https://sayedabdulkarim.github.io/abdul-portfolio/

My Work

1 - Rebrand Digital -

i - digiAlaya - created pages using html, css and worked on functionalities using javascript (10/2010 - 12/2019) - https://digialaya.com/
ii - meetUniversity - meetUniversity is an online education marketing across international territories,including University Search, University Selection, Admission Guidance, Study Abroad, Exams Preparation Tips, Course Search etc. (11/2019 - 3/2020) - https://www.meetuniversity.com/* for web app, worked on component using reactjs, redux, router, api integration, Unit Testing, GIT.

* for mobile app, worked on components using react-native
iii - Worked on their offical website
· Technologies Used: HTML5, CSS3, MaterialUI, ReactJs,
Router, Redux(thunk), api integration, Unit Testing, GIT. (10/2019 - 1/2020)

2 - Vibrant Info

i - Nodwin Vendor Portal - worked on component.
Technologies Used: HTML5, CSS3, Bootstrap, ReactSSR,
ContextApi, api integration, Unit Testing, BIT Bucket. (4 / 2020 - 3 / 2021) - https://www.nodw.in
ii - Alwar Soft - worked on component.
Technologies Used: HTML5, CSS3, MaterialUI, ReactJs,
Router, Redux(saga), api integration, Unit Testing, BIT Bucket. (7 / 2020 - 3 / 2021)

3 - Capital Numbers

- i **DewSquad (FrontEnd)** HTML5 ,CSS3, MaterialUI, ReactJs, Router, Redux(thunk), api integration, Unit Testing, BIT Bucket. (4 / 2021 10 / 2021) https://www.dewsquad.com/
- ii **DewSquad (Admin) -** HTML5 ,CSS3, MaterialUI, ReactJs, Router, Redux(thunk), api integration, Unit Testing, BIT Bucket. (4 / 2021 10 / 2021)

4- Tavant Technologies

- i **Scalable Legal** HTML5, CSS3, Material UI, ReactJs, Router, Redux(toolKit), api integration, Unit Testing, GIT, Third party Google Map Api, Twillio Chat. (11/2021 10/2022) http://dev.settlementapp99.com/
- ii winfieldUnited HTML5, CSS3, Jquery, Javascript. Foundation Framework, Bootstrap, Kentico (11,12,13) (12/2022 present) (https://www.winfieldunited.com/, https://www.winfieldunited.com/, https://www.croplan.com/, https://www.toolsstage.winfieldunited.com/)

Personal Works

Food Delivery App (Client & Admin Portals, Server API)

Client Portal: Streamlined ordering built with React, Redux Toolkit, TypeScript, Google Maps React, SCSS and Font Face Observer for async font loading. Employs JWT and cookie-based CSRF tokens to ensure secure data exchanges and authenticated requests.

URL: https://food-delivery-ab.vercel.app/

Admin Portal: Administrative control center for order and data management, mirroring the client tech stack for a cohesive experience.

URL: https://food-delivery-admin-one.vercel.app/

Server API: Robust backend in Node.js, Express, and MongoDB, with Firebase for OTP and CSRF, JWT for security. Supports secure communication and efficient data handling.

Employment History

Software Engineer

Tavant Technologies Pvt. Ltd • Bengaluru, Karnataka 11/2021 - Present

Software Engineer

Capital Number • Kolkata, West Bengal 04/2021 - 11/2021

React JS Developer

Vibrant Info • Bangalore, Karnataka 03/2020 - 04/2021

Front End Developer

Rebrand Digital • Bengaluru, Karnataka 11/2019 - 03/2020

Professional Skills

Front-End Development, Web Development, HTML, CSS, Javascript, Jquery, React.js, Routers, Redux, Context Api, Node.js, Express.js, MongoDB, PassportJs, JWT(Json Web Token), Bootstrap, Es6, JQuery, Next JS, Redux toolkit, Google Map API, Twillio, Material UI, Bootstrap, redux thunk, redux saga, webpack, babel, axios, Typescript, React Testing Library, Jest, Kentico CMS, Storybook, GraphQL, AWS

Education

BTech

PKACE,Bargarh • Bargarh, Odisha Graduated - 06/2017

Languages

English, Hindi